Akhundov **Damat**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · BACKEND DEVELOPER

Baku, Azerbaijan

□ (+994) 51 000-60-17 | ■ akhundov1damat@gmail.com | • akhunddamat | • akhundov1damat

"Software is art."

Summary ___

Current Middle Backend Developer at product company Online Gymnasium. I have experience in developing microservice architecture, working with databases, parallel tasks, converting files, integrating external services, working with caching, as well as training new employees. Special- izing in RESTful API realization. Using Django REST Framework and FastAPI for this purpose. Prefer to use FastAPI and developing structure of system manually. Also prefer to use Linux, namely Manjaro. Interested in challenging tasks related to architecture development and learning new technologies.

Work Experience _____

Online Gymnasium Remote

Feb. 2020 - Present.

MIDDLE BACKEND DEVELOPER

- Developed database structure via Django ORM.
- · Worked with Celery tasks. Applied best practises.
- Implemented integration between BigBlueButton and Django REST Framework.
- Used Test Driven Development.
- Built structure of the project via style guide.
- Implemented RESTful API microservice.
- Worked with Docker and Docker Compose.
- Realised ORM optimization.
- Developed an application for converting files from two services (JOD Converter and CloudConvert)

Freelance

JuNior BaCKEND DEVELOPER

- Developed payment system.
- Worked with OpenCV on Python.
- Realized authentication system for FastAPI.

Baku, Azerbaijan Feb. 2019 - Feb. 2020

Skills

DevOps Docker, Docker Compose

Frameworks Django REST Framework, Django, FastAPI, REST API **Methodologies** Test Driven Development, Domain Driven Development

Principles SOLID, YAGNI, DRY **Databases** Postgres, Redis, Cassandra

Programming Languages Python, C

Languages English, Russian, Azerbaijani

Education _____

Oct. 2020 - Oct. 2024

Ramin Mahmudzadeh school of solving Olympiad problems

Sep. 2018 - 2019

OLYMPIAD PROBLEMS SOLVER
• Learned to solve problems of

 Learned to solve problems of different level of complexity.

DECEMBER 16, 2021 AKHUNDOV MURAD · RÉSUMÉ

1

Baku, Azerbaijan